(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-22T09:57:48.212050",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
つかまえて、ほら
"Catch it, look,"
この shooting star
this shooting star,
a world of our fiction awaits
ずっと同じ毎日に迷いがあっても
Even if I'm lost in the same daily routine,
気づかないふりをしてたんだ
I acted like I didn't notice.
ほんのちょっとの勇気がまだ出せなくって
Still unable to muster even a little bit of true courage,
まどろむ宇宙でさまよっていた
I wandered in a slumbering universe.
夜空に浮かぶ
Floating in the night sky,
星に願いをかけるんだ
I make a wish upon a star.
i hope… 抱いている夢を
I hope... the dream I hold onto
絶対諦めたくない
I absolutely don't want to give up.
走り出すから
Because I'm going to start running,
追いかけて 今
Chase after it now,
あの shooting star
that shooting star.
見たことのないストーリー
A story I've never seen before,
進んでいくんだ
I'm going to advance into it.
いつの日にかきっと
Someday for sure,
描いた世界へ
To the world I envisioned,
辿り着けるように
So that I can reach it.
let go
of the days you thought mattered so
life goes on, tomorrow's rolling in
is it the world we know, or the dream we sought so long?
もっと誰でもない自分になりたいんだ
I want to become someone who is truly myself,
新しい風が心を揺らした
A new wind shook my heart.
it takes something to believe
the wish we were promised could really come to life
and so, if this is how the story goes
to find that strength inside, I'll remember why back then
you took my hand, and you said
つかまえて、ほら
"Catch it, look,"
この shooting star
this shooting star.
さあ、まずは一歩踏み出して恐れずにゆこう
Come on, first take a step forward and go without fear.
いつの日にかきっと
Someday for sure,
まだ見ぬ世界へ辿り着けるように
So that I can reach a world I've yet to see.
夜明けに咲いた月が
The moon that bloomed at dawn
眩いブルーの空に溶けてく
Melts into the dazzling blue sky.
you and i, an undecided future
doesn't matter if the final truth hurts
もうすぐ朝が動き出すから
Morning is about to start moving soon,
抱きしめて 今 この shooting star
So hold tight now to this shooting star.
見たことのないストーリー
A story I've never seen before,
I'll be here betting on that fearsome heart
'cause you're that shooting star
It's hopeless now, but maybe
if you take that step into the darkness
you'll find me running by your side until the dawn
in the end, it's you and me, us against tomorrow
皆さん、どうもこんにちは！
Hello everyone, hello!
調子どうですか？
How are you guys doing?
ホロライブEnglishの森カリオペです！
It's Mori Calliope from Hololive English!
はぁ、すごく楽しかったね！
Ah, that was so much fun!
このライブめっちゃめちゃ素敵ですね！
This live stream is just so, so wonderful!
メタバースすごーい！
The metaverse is amazing!
わぁお！
Wow!
ああ、この曲ね、懐かしいねホロライブオルタナティブ。
Ah, this song... it brings back memories, Hololive Alternative.
でも、あの、日本語の歌詞も英語の歌詞、本当に特別だから、
But, um, both the Japanese and English lyrics are truly special,
今からもよく聞いてほしいね！
so I hope you'll keep listening closely from now on!
じゃあ、皆さん、メタバースライブ楽しんでくださいね！
Well everyone, please enjoy the Metaverse Live!
ゆらゆら 動いた この心も
This swaying, shifting heart of mine...
わたしはあのこになれなかったんだ
I couldn't become that girl after all.
ゆらゆら 風吹く 連れてっていく
A gentle breeze blows, carrying me away.
いいな いいな わたしはさ 何も持ってなかった
How nice, how nice... I didn't have a thing.
傾いている気分を無視した
Ignoring this tilted mood of mine,
今日も無理してあー頑張っちゃうからさぁ
I'm pushing myself hard and trying my best again today.
フレ！わたし！フレ！わたし！進めるさ
Yay, me! Yay, me! I can keep moving forward.
今すぐに手に入れたいけど、お預けかもね
I want to get my hands on it right now, but maybe it has to wait.
もしもし今叶うなら届けたい、届けて愛
If my wish could come true right now, I want to deliver it—deliver this love!
キラキラ 輝け あの星みたいに
Sparkle and shine, just like that star!
あのこはわたしにならなかったんだ
That girl couldn't become me after all.
キラキラ 顔出す 一等星も
Even the first-magnitude star peeking out with a sparkle—
そうかそうね あなたもさ ずっと一緒だった
Ah, that's right, you were by my side all along too.
ひらひら 変わった この心そうど
This fluttering, changing heart of mine—
わたしはあのこになれなかったんだ
I couldn't become that girl after all.
ひらひら 季節を増やしてみる
Let's try adding more fluttering seasons.
そうどそうど わたしはさ すべて持っている
That's right, that's right, I have everything!
ゆらゆら 変わった この未来どうも
This swaying, changing future of mine—
わたしはあのこになれなかったんだ
I couldn't become that girl after all.
ゆらゆら 掴んだ この運命と
With this swaying destiny I've grasped,
生きてみたい みんなとさ
I want to live on, together with everyone,
今を離さないように
so we never let go of the present moment.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
みんな楽しんでますか？イェーイ！
Are you all having fun? Yay!
「プロトライブ」ということで、
As a "proto-live",
みんなね、こう自由に動きながら、好きな場所で見れるということで、新しい形のライブですね。
everyone can move around freely and watch from wherever they like. It's a new style of live performance.
普段と違って、もういろんな角度から見られているというライブ、大変緊張しております。
Unlike usual, being seen from all sorts of angles—I'm quite nervous.
はい、そして、え、先ほどの楽曲はあずきのオリジナル曲「カナップス」でした。皆さん、いかがでしたでしょうか？
Yes, and, um, the previous song was Azuki's original song "Kanaps." How did you all like it?
はい、ちょっとね、この空間でカナップスを歌って、かなりテンションが上がりました。
Yes, um, singing "Kanaps" in this space really got my tension up.
はい、ということで、次で早くも最後の曲ということなんですけれども、みんな最後まで盛り上がってくれますかー！？
So, with that, next is already the final song, but everyone, will you get hyped all the way to the end!?
オーーー！
Ooh!
はい、ということで最後まで盛り上がっていきましょう！
Yes, with that, let's get hyped all the way to the end!
story time
幾千の星の物語
Thousands of star-filled stories,
永い永い旅のわりに
at the end of a long, long journey—
僕の瞳に降り注いで
shower down into my eyes
魔法をかける
and cast a spell.
この胸の星の物語
This star-filled story in my heart,
高鳴る鼓動のその先に
beyond this throbbing heartbeat—
待ってるその続きをもっと知りたいんだ
I want to know more of what awaits us next.
僕の声になる前のささやきがざわめきにとけてしまうまえに
Before the whisper that becomes my voice melts into the noise,
きらめく流れ星になって穹を駆けろ
become a twinkling shooting star and race across the firmament!
たとえ今はどんなに小さくてもほんのささやかなはばたきでも
Even if it's ever so small right now, even with just a slight flutter of wings,
世界はきっと僕ら次第どんなときでも
the world will surely depend on us, no matter when!
ささやきつぶやきほんの少しの勇気はばたきはばたき世界はあっけなくかわる
Whispering, murmuring, a tiny bit of courage, fluttering, fluttering—the world changes in a flash.
ざわめきゆらめきいくつもの波をこえてきらめきときめき君にとどけ
Surging, flickering, crossing wave after wave, sparkling, throbbing—reaching you!
重力からときはたれて
Released from gravity,
おとなの呪いを脱ぎ捨てて
shedding the curses of adulthood,
こどものときのその気持ちでめくるページで
with that childhood feeling, turning the page—
過去のすべてが星座のようにつながって答えを描いた
all of our past connected like constellations to sketch out the answer.
涙の海の味も笑顔の空の色も
The taste of the sea of tears, the color of the sky of smiles—
この胸に光ってる
they are shining in this heart.
僕の声音になる前のささやきがざわめきにとけてしまうまえに
Before the whisper that becomes my voice melts into the noise,
きらめく流れ星になって君を見つける
become a twinkling shooting star and find you!
たとえ今はどんなに小さくてもほんのささやかなはばたきでも
Even if it's ever so small right now, even with just a slight flutter of wings,
世界はきっと僕ら次第どんなときでも
the world will surely depend on us, no matter when!
僕の声になる前のささやきがざわめきにとけてしまうまえに
Before the whisper that becomes my voice melts into the noise,
きらめく流れ星になって君を見つける
become a twinkling shooting star and find you!
たとえ今はどんなに小さくてもほんのささやかなはばたきでも
Even if it's ever so small right now, even with just a slight flutter of wings,
世界はきっと僕ら次第どんなときでも
the world will surely depend on us, no matter when!
いつでもどんなときでも僕ら次第だから
Always, no matter when, because it depends on us!
ささやきつぶやきほんの少しの勇気はばたきはばたき世界はあっけなくかわる
Whispering, murmuring, a tiny bit of courage, fluttering, fluttering—the world changes in a flash.
ざわめきゆらめきいくつもの波をこえてきらめきときめき君にとどけ
Surging, flickering, crossing wave after wave, sparkling, throbbing—reaching you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
楽しかったね。
That was so fun!
あ、皆さん、モリ・カリオペです！
Ah, everyone, it's Mori Calliope!
わぁ、あずき先輩、すごい！本当に素敵でしたね。
Wow, Azuki-senpai, amazing! It really was wonderful.
ありがとう〜！
Thank you~!
この曲はね、本当に好きです。いろんな才能があるSingerがいるから…
This song, you know, I really love it. Because there are singers with all sorts of talent...
素敵な曲になった。
It turned into such a wonderful song.
私もずっと歌ってみたいと思ってたけど
I've always wanted to sing it too,
今回ね頑張りました。
but I worked really hard this time.
というわけで今回のライブは以上となります。
So that concludes today's live performance.
あっという間の時間でしたが、
It went by in a flash,
今後もホロアースではいろんなライブやイベントを行っていくみたいなので皆さん期待して待っててください！
but Holoearth will keep holding various events, so everyone please look forward to it!
そしてメタバースでのライブということで現実の会場でのライブになかなか足を運べない人たちも
And since this is a metaverse live, even those who can't easily visit real-world venues
これから同じ空間で一緒にライブが楽しめるようになるということで今から私たちも楽しみです！
will now be able to enjoy lives together in the same space, so we're looking forward to it too!
皆さん楽しかった？
Did you all have fun?
それでは皆さん今日はありがとうございました！
Well everyone, thank you so much for today!
またね！聞いてくれてありがとう！
See you again! Thanks for listening!
本日はご参加いただきありがとうございました！ #ホロアースライブ
Thank you for joining us today! #HoloearthLive